Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
I've got a bad feeling about this place.
Father! I brought a sacrifice!
"Father"? So suddenly...
Who is it?
Dad?
Father
Envy.
Envy?!
This is him?!
Brother!
Al?
Al in the armor... which means...
We were able to get back.
Yeah.
Brother!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
I'm so glad to see you're safe!
That hurts, Al!
Your armor's hurting me!
It's just that I'm so glad to see you're alive...
You're right.
Sorry.
For worrying you.
But where the heck are we?
What a surprise.
Humans came out of his stomach?
Hohen...heim?!
An arm and a leg made of steel, and a suit of armor.
Are you the Elric Brothers?
It's not him?
Are you mistaking me for somebody?
Hang on...
Hohen...
Don't tell me you're talking about Van Hohenheim?
What is your relationship with him?
He's... our dad.
Dad?!
What a surprise! He ended up having kids?!
But aren't your last names Elric?
Elric is our mother's maiden name!
I see.
So, where is he now?
Hell if I know!
But more importantly, who the hell are you?!
You look just like Hohenheim!
There's no way he'd die.
Listen to me!
And he's even had kids...
Brother, this man is...
Oh? You're injured?
And you're missing your left arm.
How's that?
Ow!
A broken bone, huh?
I-It's fixed.
Hey!
Oww!
Now for your ribs.
You two are important to us.
Don't be too reckless with your bodies, okay?
He used alchemy without a single hand motion.
And he didn't make the rest of my armor thinner, either...
In other words, it's not equivalent exchange.
Who the hell are you?
It's unreal! How could your insides be in such a state?!
I'm going to ask you the same exact question.
Who are you?
You can eat him.
Okay!
H-Hang on!
He's my friend!
I'm a human sacrifice, so don't kill him for my sake. Okay?
That's not my problem.
He's useless to me.
What did you say?!
Brother, the Homunculi call him "Father".
He's the one who created them.
What?!
Even though he patched us up...
I don't like it.
Your attitude...
You're the same as those who laugh at humans for being foolish.
Do you consider insects crawling about the Earth to be foolish?
Even if insects struggle, the difference between you and them is so great that you don't exactly give a damn.
That's precisely how I feel about you humans.
I appreciate you healing our wounds,
but I don't think I can get along with you!
Seems you're the cause of everything!
I'll take care of you quickly.
I can't be worrying about the small fry!
You're calling me small fry now, runt?
Runt?!
I've got their leader!
Ling!
What is going on?!
How can he use alchemy without a single hand motion?!
What a waste of time.
We can't use alchemy?!
Ed! Al!
What did that geezer do?!
Why...
Why can't we use alchemy?!
Seriously, these tiny beings are unbelievable.
They start to think they're at the top of the world as soon as they gain some power.
They don't even know what exactly they're using.
Do you really think all this prosperity was created with the powers of humans only?
How laughable, fools.
What the hell are you talking about?!
You promised you'd tell me as soon as we got out!
What?
I don't remember making promises with you insects.
You bastard...
You're talking too much, Envy.
Yeah, yeah...
He could be good for the job.
I may be able to create another pawn.
That's... a philosopher's stone!
What?!
So you're planning to do it, huh?
Do what?
He's creating a Homunculus.
He's going to inject the philosopher's stone into him.
If all goes well, a homunculus with a human base will be complete.
Well, most humans end up dying because they aren't capable of fighting the stone's power.
Like I'll let you!
Let go, Envy!!
Dammit, what's going on?!
Why can't we use alchemy?!
Hey, you!
Geezer! Stop it!
He has people waiting for his return!
Let go!!!
Humans can't shoot me if I do this...
Right?
Damn you...
It's fine! Don't shoot!
Don't interfere.
This is fine by me!
What?
I came to this country looking for a philosopher's stone.
And he's just going to give it to me like that.
It's exactly what I wished for!
What the hell are you saying?!
Oh? Sounds interesting.
Then as you wish, it's all yours.
Stop it!
Ling!
I... I told you not...
...to interfere!
It's fine... Just wait for me...
I'm the man who will become the Emperor of Xing...
...Ling Yao!
What the hell is a brat doing here?!
Ah, well.
Let me have your body.
I'll put it to good use.
Fine...
It's all yours!
What?
I'm saying that I'll accept you!
Wouldn't people normally be against it?
I'm going to become the Emperor of Xing.
How do you expect me to do that if I can't even accept a few dozen people in my body?!
I like decisive guys.
But you'd better not regret it.
Regret?
If I return empty-handed, how could I possibly face my servant who cut her own arm off to save me?!
I want power...
Absolute power that will help me protect and gain more!
I knew the risks from the beginning!
I like your greed.
Well then, show me how prepared you are!
Ling?
Huh? Oh, the guy who owned this body?
Sorry, but now it belongs to me, Greed.
Not Ling, but...
Greed?!
You're that Greed?
What do you mean by "that" Greed?
You don't remember?!
The one at Dublith...
Yeah, so what Greed are you talking about?
The Greed that came before you.
Oh, I see.
Well, as you can see,
I'm a different Greed from the one you guys know.
What happened to Ling?
He was an interesting brat.
He accepted me in a matter of seconds.
No way! There's no way he's that easy to take control of!
Answer me! Ling!
Ling!!!
What?
No...
I don't like him...
He's a person, but at the same time, he's not!
You're right, a lot of these guys aren't human.
Shao May!
I'm so glad to see you're safe!
Do you have any idea how worried I was?
Whoa, I don't really get it, but is this some tearful reunion?
It seems they aren't working together with the Homunculi.
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Huh? Where?
Where's Sir Edward?
Right there.
I don't see him anywhere!
I'm pointing right at him.
That small one is the Fullmetal Alchemist.
You toyed with my pure heart, you midget!
Speak for yourself, midget!
PLACEHOLDER
What did you do to her, Brother?!
He's the Ishbalan I didn't get to eat.
I didn't do a thing!
The disobedient people, huh...
He's the one who uses destructive alchemy and continues to interfere with our plans, right?
Take care of them, Gluttony.
He can't use alchemy right now.
Okay!
What?!
I'll never forgive you!
You stepped all over a maiden's heart,
and on top of that, you kidnapped Shao May!
Divine punishment...
...for all of you!!!
Lucky!
We still can't use it!
What gives?!
How can you two use alchemy here?
What do you mean?
Seriously, what's going on?
How can Scar and that little girl...
I have no idea.
No idea, but...
This could be our chance to fill them in.
Scar!
I'll tell you the truth behind the Ishbal rebellion!
The truth?
The death of the child which became the trigger of the rebellion...
...was caused by him, disguised as a military officer!
They're behind it all!
It seems like I'll have to ask you to explain this in detail.
Answer me.
Why did my people have to fall?
Depending on your answer, I'll send you to...
No.
I won't send you to God, where my fellow Ishbalans reside!
Think of yourselves as undeserving of eternal rest or redemption!!!
Wow, amazing!
Not bad for a human.
Greed, get rid of the intruders.
Yeah, yeah...
I refuse to believe it, Ling!
I'm Greed.
That's...
Could that be Ling from the Yao clan?
A little girl!
Soft body!
Hey you, how can you use alchemy?
Yes, you really are using it.
Human destruction...
No, decomposition.
A second later, and I would have been...
Mr. Scar!
Shao May... Run...
You're mine!
Are you okay?!
I never asked you to save me...
What are you talking about?!
They're ruthless toward humans who are of no benefit to them.
Hurry up and get out of here!
There's way too many of them!
You two didn't run away?!
Scar, could you take this girl and get out of here?
You're going to let me escape?
Even if I killed those doctors...
Yeah, I want to beat the hell out of you.
To be honest, I don't even want to ask you for any favors.
But right now, it's more important to take this girl somewhere safe.
What will you do?
Apparently, my brother and I are important to them in some way.
Even if we stay here, they won't kill us.
Right now, I won't be able to protect
that girl and escape from here at the same time.
And I don't have the slightest intention of running away, either!
He decomposed water?!
Geez, let me know before you do stuff like that!
How reckless!
Igniting hydrogen? That's clever of you.
Where is he?
Where did he go?!
I don't know!
Gluttony, track him by scent!
You're out of lives?!
You've died too much!
That was a nice kick.
I think this'll be more fun than I expected.
You stupid prince!
Come back to your senses!
I'm Greed.
I don't care!
Give Ling back his body.
No can do!
What are you, an idiot?!
What are you going to do about your country?!
What about Lan Fan?!
PLACEHOLDER
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Father! I got him.
Take him upstairs, where Wrath is.
Seriously... Always screwing around with us...
As long as you guys behave, we won't do a thing.
Brother.
He...
Ling...
...is inside of him.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
You used up your regeneration abilities, huh?
Worry not, my son.
I will recreate you.
With your memories, of course.
Humans in chaos, struggle and writhe in agony.
Because that serves as proof that one is alive.
And struggle and kneel before me.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Struggle of the Fool
Episode 29, Struggle of the Fool.
Will the man who had his limbs twisted be able to stand again?